在所有的Android设备里
Of all the Android launch devices, the Nexus 1 will
Nexus 1在我心里一直有非常特别的位置
always hold a special place in my heart. That's not
我的第一台android设备，HTC G1
to take anything away from my first Android device, the
它的推出把android带到了这个世界，带有独特的
HTC G1, that launched Android into the world with its
下巴和滑出式键盘。
distinctive chin and slide-out keyboard, or the HTC Magic. First
HTC Magic，是我加入Google时
pre release android phone I got to dog food when
第一台预发布的android手机
I joined google. And the first, the wave of devices
也是我们给每一位2009年google IO与会者的第一波设备
we gave every attendee starting at google IO in 2009.
2010年android迎来了有趣的全球现象
2010 was the year android went from that's
从5月开始10万的日激活量
interesting to global phenomenon. Growing from 100,000 activations a
到12月超过30万的日激活量
day in May, to over 300,000 by December.
Motorola Droid的发布功不可没
That was seriously helped by the release of the
我依然记得
Motorola Droid. I can still remember the offices
就是这里，44层的办公室里
here in building 44 echoing with the constant refrain
不断重复的Droid设备重启的声音
of Droid as each device rebooted. The Droid was
Droid是第一台又薄，分辨率又高，性能又强大的
the first of the thinner, higher res, more powerful
android设备，这些都成了日后的标准
Android devices that have since become standard. And it
它也是Verizon在美国发布的设备，
was also the device whose release on Verizon here in
真正开始了Android激活的洪水
the U,S. Really kicked off the flood of Android
但我那是是一个伦敦人
activations. But I was a Londoner then, and the Droid
Droid是一台只支持CDMA的电话
was a CDMA only phone, so it was never
所以我从没有真正的用过它
really a device I truly used. Then, there was the
然后就是Nexus One,代号为激情
Nexus One, code-named Passion. The first device I felt was
我觉得它是第一部纯净的android设备
pure Android was also the phone we brought with us
我们带它进行了2010Android开发者实验室世界巡演
on our 2010 Android Developer Labs World Tour. Me
我和我的同事旅行世界各地
and my colleagues travel across the world. Seven cities
十天走了七个城市，通过演讲和Nexus One
in ten days. Introducing over twenty thousand developers to
吸引了二万多个Android开发者
Android by way of presentations and a free Nexus 1.
因此我在欧洲交了很多朋友
As a result, I made a lot of friends
也深刻了解到我能携带多少电话
across Europe and learned exactly how many boxes of phones
穿越在斯德哥尔摩雪堆和柏林结冰的路面上
I can carry across snow drifts in Stockholm and
从那时起，nexus 4和nexus 5
icy roads in Berlin. Since then, The Nexus S4 and
都有各自不同的提升来打造更好的android手机
five have each improved on what it takes, to make
世界各地的OEM（原始设备制造商）们
a great android phone. And OEMs across the world, have
已经创造了超过1000种不同的android设备
created 1000s of different Android devices. Starting with the Motorola
从motorola zoom开始，android进军平板，
Zoom, which led Android's official expansion into tablets, and leading the
它也为nexus 7和nexus 10指引着道路。
way for the Nexus 7 and 10. But that was
但这仅仅是开始。这些改变为android移动设备
just the start, Those changes paved the way for the
铺平了道路，成长为一切背后的大脑
Android mobile [UNKNOWN] west, to grow into what could be,
从手机到平板，再到电视，车载，可穿戴设备
the brains behind anything, from phones and tablets, to TVs, cars
比如Android wear。很难想象下一个是什么
and wearables, like Android wear. It's impossible to know, what comes
谁知道呢？ 也许下一个android设备，就是机器人
next. Who knows? Maybe the next Android devices, will be Androids themselves.